

Helena, MT 59601 - shanemisrael@gmail.com - WWW: shaneisrael.dev

## **Summary**

Passionate programmer with a love for end-to-end product ownership, excellent user experiences, and learning new technologies. Designed and driven multiple internal applications that have become necessary core components to SoFi. Built and managed Stage's entire infrastructure while implementing their frontend web application via React.

## Skills

- NodeJS
- React
- Python
- Java / Kotlin
- HTML / CSS

- PostgreSQL / MySQL / SQLite3
- Docker / Docker Compose
- Kubernetes
- GitHub Actions (CI/CD)
- AWS / Digital Ocean

## Experience

Stage Technologies

November 2021 to Current

Staff Software Engineer

Helena, MT

SoFi

SoFi

- Built and maintained the production, staging, and test infrastructure used to deploy our frontend and backend docker containers via Kubernetes, Nginx, and secret injection via Doppler.
- Built and maintained the CI/CD pipeline through Github Actions used to build, validate, and test merge requests as well as deploy to our live environments.
- Designed and implemented user interfaces for the Stage web application in React.
- Designed and implemented various PostgreSQL tables as needed for new features.
- Implemented some backend Kotlin controllers and services as needed.
- Documented software development processes and procedures for future use in onboarding of new employees.
- Collaborated with team members to ensure successful project completion within timeline constraints. Worked directly with backend engineers and UI/UX designers.

Senior Software Engineer

June 2018 to September 2021

- Designed and developed an internal tool to automatically provision AWS instances to run the company's entire software stack for development and QA purposes, which has been adopted by the entire engineering organization
- Developed unique solutions from internal feedback in order to improve our automated systems to better support our engineering and business staff
- Continued to maintain and improve internal automated third-party integration system and web tool.

Software Engineer

May 2015 to June 2018

- Maintained internal software for loan application processing and world-facing software for customer application creation
- Designed and developed password and database access control system, adopted across the company for user access control
- Designed and developed an automated solution using Docker and RunDeck to ingest and deliver thousands of daily NACHA files, cash distribution files, and loan servicing information to and from third parties, including a robust UI for error reporting and retries.

## **Education and Training**

 $Montana\ State\ University\ -\ Bozeman$ 

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Bozeman, MT

May 2015